[Music]
foreign
and what today we're going to be doing
is we're going to show how to go from a
ketos
from a Fischer projection of a ketos to
a Hayworth projection meaning that we
have a ketone in that structure so in my
last video I talked about going through
how to go from Fisher to Hayworth but I
wanted to try to do a quick one just to
give you that summary because it's a
little bit of a harder one so the first
thing that we're going to do we're going
to write down that Fischer projection so
when we have that fixture projection how
to draw fructose as a Hayworth the first
thing that we're going to go through is
number our chain so this is our official
numbering so we have one two three four
five six however the thing that's going
to be reacting is going to be our last
chiral o h so on here we have our last
chiral carbon so our last member of our
ring structure is going to be this o
here and what that's going to make is
The Ether in it so let's highlight and
blue all the members of our ring
structure so the alcohol is going to be
reacting with the aldehyde in this
structure okay
so these are going to be our members so
if we count the blue parts right we if
we start at that Ketone that's number
one so this can be the Ketone carbon 3
carbon 4 Carbon 5 and then the Outlast
alcohol so we have five members in our
structure so when we have five we're
going to be drawing the house shape
which is like the one here now when we
draw that shape so
we're going to be the first before we
get to that we have to be able to
determine what all of our pieces are
where are they going to be located are
they up or down
so we're going to draw this 90 degrees
to the right
so we're going to redraw our
fructose
so we have that c double bond o notice
how it's pointing down to help indicate
where the bottom is
so we have that ch2oh
I'm just going to shorten this a little
bit so ch2oh on both sides
and now we're going to illustrate the
chiral carbons with our crosses so when
h o h
o h on that right side which is now the
new bottom then we draw the opposite on
top
so this is going to be the bottom of our
ring
now keep in mind this is going to be
number one two three four and five of
our house shape
being that originally this structure is
a d fructose
that means that you know on our house
that we're going to draw the ch2oh is
going to be pointing up okay so whenever
it is D ch2oh points up if it was L
ch2oh points down so with that let's
draw our basic house
so we're going to take that structure
it's going to look something like this
right the O is going to be right in the
middle
just like so
and like we said earlier we can put in
all of our pieces so we said the ch2
oops we can say the ch2 is going to be
pointing up
and here why don't we show that in red
just to help us
illustrate where all these things are
so we have ch2
o h that's pointing upwards now keep in
mind both animal Merrick versions of
this exist so we're going to first draw
where the o h is pointing up like so
now the rest of the pieces we're going
to copy down so we had all of our
carbons right so this is one then we
have two three four five
this is going to be one or sorry this is
going to not be one actually I made a
mistake so
let's erase this and fix that right
because we have this value over here we
have one two three four five six so we
got to put in here
that
we have an oh a ch2oh pointing
down
and then our other o h pointing up
so this is going to be one two three
four five six so we have all the carbons
represented now on carbon three we had
the o h
pointing up
hydrogen down
on carbon four we have the o h pointing
down the hydrogen up
and then on carbon 5 we had our ch2oh
pointing up and then our hydrogen is
pointing down so this is one structure
and we'll fold in the bottom just to
give it that a little bit more of that
Hayworth look to it so it boldens it a
little
so that is the beta representation so
this is beta D fructose
and we'll
kind of clean it up a little so this is
beta
d fructose
now for Alpha D fructose it's going to
be very very similar
so Alpha D fructose we're going to take
the same structure the only thing we're
going to be changing is now the o h
is going to be pointing
down and the ch2oh is going to be
pointing up so we're switching the
anomeric carbon around
so we can see we have that o h pointing
down
and then we'll put the rest of the chain
in so you have the rest of that ring and
it's really easy if you just remember
what which one of those basic shapes is
it going to be a hexagon or is it going
to be a house or a five-member ring
because it allows you to just quickly
write those down for when you're doing
exams or doing quizzes or or whatever
whatever it is that your professors
might have you doing okay so we draw
that structure we put the H's in the o h
is in
and the H they all stay the same the
only thing that is changing is where our
anomeric carbon is pointing so we have
the animers of each other so we have the
alpha
and then the beta representation here
they're both being drawn so and that's
how you can go through and draw fructose
between these two different versions so
I hope this video helped you with a
ketone or ketos so these are going to
make five member Rings If it started
with an aldose it would be six member so
you can see an example of that other
video all right I hope you had and hope
to see you again in the future please
feel free to like And subscribe to the
channel for more introductory organic
and
biochemistry help all right bye now
foreign